<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-04-14T13:11:15+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Multimedia and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory</title><subtitle>MAILAB at National Taiwan Normal University conducts cutting-edge research in multimedia analysis, artificial intelligence, and machine learning with applications in computer vision and signal processing.</subtitle><author><name>MAILAB NTNU</name></author><entry><title type="html">Workshop on Multimodal Learning: Registration Open</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/events/2025/04/05/multimodal-workshop.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Workshop on Multimodal Learning: Registration Open" /><published>2025-04-05T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2025-04-05T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/events/2025/04/05/multimodal-workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/events/2025/04/05/multimodal-workshop.html"><![CDATA[<p>MAILAB is hosting a two-day workshop on “Multimodal Learning for Computer Vision Applications” on May 15-16, 2025. This workshop will bring together researchers and practitioners to discuss the latest advances in combining visual, textual, and audio data for comprehensive AI systems.</p>

<h3 id="workshop-details">Workshop Details</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Dates</strong>: May 15-16, 2025</li>
  <li><strong>Location</strong>: Technology Building, NTNU Campus</li>
  <li><strong>Registration</strong>: Open until May 1st or until capacity is reached</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="featured-speakers">Featured Speakers</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Professor Alex Johnson (National Taiwan University)</li>
  <li>Dr. Michelle Chen (Google Research)</li>
  <li>Dr. Kevin Liu (NVIDIA)</li>
  <li>Professor Jane Chen (NTNU)</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="topics">Topics</h3>

<p>The workshop will cover multimodal fusion techniques, transformer architectures for cross-modal understanding, self-supervised learning with multimodal data, and applications in healthcare, autonomous systems, and content creation.</p>

<p>Registration is now open on our website. Early registration is encouraged as space is limited to 50 participants.</p>]]></content><author><name>MAILAB NTNU</name></author><category term="Events" /><category term="events" /><category term="workshop" /><category term="multimodal-learning" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[MAILAB is hosting a two-day workshop on “Multimodal Learning for Computer Vision Applications” on May 15-16, 2025. This workshop will bring together researchers and practitioners to discuss the latest advances in combining visual, textual, and audio data for comprehensive AI systems.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MAILAB Team Wins Best Paper Award at CVPR 2025</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/awards/2025/04/01/cvpr-best-paper.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MAILAB Team Wins Best Paper Award at CVPR 2025" /><published>2025-04-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2025-04-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/awards/2025/04/01/cvpr-best-paper</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/awards/2025/04/01/cvpr-best-paper.html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re proud to announce that our lab’s paper “Self-supervised Learning for Resource-Constrained Visual Recognition” has received the Best Paper Award at the 2025 IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR).</p>

<p>The paper, authored by Dr. Sarah Kim, Robert Zhang, and Professor Jane Chen, presents a novel approach to training deep learning models with limited labeled data, achieving state-of-the-art performance while requiring significantly fewer computational resources.</p>

<p>CVPR is one of the most prestigious conferences in the field of computer vision, and this recognition highlights our lab’s commitment to pushing the boundaries of what’s possible in visual recognition systems.</p>

<p>The award committee praised the work for its innovative methodology and potential impact on making advanced computer vision accessible in resource-constrained environments like mobile devices and IoT applications.</p>]]></content><author><name>MAILAB NTNU</name></author><category term="Awards" /><category term="awards" /><category term="computer-vision" /><category term="conferences" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re proud to announce that our lab’s paper “Self-supervised Learning for Resource-Constrained Visual Recognition” has received the Best Paper Award at the 2025 IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Research Project: Advanced Visual Recognition Models for Medical Imaging</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/research/2025/03/15/medical-imaging-project.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Research Project: Advanced Visual Recognition Models for Medical Imaging" /><published>2025-03-15T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/research/2025/03/15/medical-imaging-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research/2025/03/15/medical-imaging-project.html"><![CDATA[<p>Our lab has launched a new research project exploring advanced visual recognition models for medical imaging. This project aims to develop deep learning algorithms that can assist radiologists in diagnosing various conditions from X-rays, CT scans, and MRIs.</p>

<p>The team will be focusing on creating models that can not only detect abnormalities but also provide explanations for their predictions, making them more trustworthy for clinical use. This research is funded by a new grant from the National Science Foundation.</p>

<p>The project will combine computer vision techniques with natural language processing to generate comprehensive reports from medical images, similar to those written by radiologists. We believe this approach will significantly reduce the time needed for diagnosis while maintaining high accuracy.</p>

<p>Graduate students interested in working on this project should contact Professor Chen for potential opportunities.</p>]]></content><author><name>MAILAB NTNU</name></author><category term="Research" /><category term="computer-vision" /><category term="medical-imaging" /><category term="deep-learning" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our lab has launched a new research project exploring advanced visual recognition models for medical imaging. This project aims to develop deep learning algorithms that can assist radiologists in diagnosing various conditions from X-rays, CT scans, and MRIs.]]></summary></entry></feed>